<resources>
    <string name="app_name">OGCNice</string>
    <string name="ogc_desc">
        OGC Nice, officially known as Olympique Gymnaste Club Nice Côte d\'Azur, is a
        professional football club from Nice, France, founded in 1904. Competing in France\'s
        top division, Ligue 1, the club plays its home matches at the Allianz Riviera Stadium.
        Nicknamed \"Les Aiglons,\" OGC Nice has a long and proud history, having won several
        Ligue 1 titles and Coupe de France trophies throughout its existence.
    </string>

    <string name="ogc_history_content">
        OGC Nice was founded in the residential district of Les Baumettes on 9 July 1904 under the name Gymnaste Club.
        The club was founded by Marquis de Massingy d\'Auzac, who served as president of the Fédération Sportive des Alpes-Maritimes (Alpes-Maritimes Sporting Federation).
        As its name suggests, the club primarily focused on gymnastics and athletics.
        \n\n
        On 6 July 1908, to remain affiliated with the FSAM and also join the amateur federation USFSA, the head of French football at the time oversaw a split: Gymnaste Club de Nice became two sections, with the new section named Gymnastes Amateurs Club de Nice.
        This section spawned a football club, and after two seasons, the two merged again.
        \n\n
        On 20 September 1919, Nice merged with Gallia Football Athlétic Club and adopted the red and black combination.
        In 2020, the club competed in the Ligue du Sud-Est, under the French Football Federation, developing rivalries with Cannes and Marseille.
        On 22 December 1924, the club changed its name to Olympique Gymnaste Club de Nice.
        \n\n
        In July 1930, the National Council of the French Football Federation voted in favor of professionalism in French football.
        Nice, along with most southern clubs, adopted this statute and became a founding member of the new league.
        In the inaugural season, Nice finished seventh in its group, and the following season finished 13th and were relegated.
        After a short absence, Nice returned to Division 2 in 1936 and played there until professional football was abolished in 1939 due to World War II.
        During the war, the club competed as amateurs in regional leagues.
        \n\n
        After World War II, Nice regained professional status and re-entered Division 2.
        They were promoted to the top flight for the 1948–49 season under Austrian manager Anton Marek.
        Under Jean Lardi, Nice won its first-ever league title in 1950–51, led by Marcel Domingo, Antoine Bonifaci, Abdelaziz Ben Tifour, Jean Courteaux, Pancho Gonzales, Luis Carniglia, and Pär Bengtsson.
        Nice won the league over Lille by having more victories.
        \n\n
        In the 1951–52 season, with manager Numa Andoire, Nice achieved the double by winning both Ligue 1 and the Coupe de France, defeating Bordeaux 5–3 in the final.
        In 1954, Nice won another Coupe de France, defeating Marseille 2–1 with goals from Victor Nuremberg and Carniglia.
        Carniglia then became manager and led the club to its third league title in his first season.
        Three seasons later, Nice won its fourth league title in 1959.
        The 1950s ended with four league titles and two Coupe de France trophies.
        Nice also made its first European appearance in 1956–57, losing to Real Madrid in the quarter-finals.
        \n\n
        In the following decades, Nice could not replicate its golden era as Reims and Saint-Étienne rose to dominance.
        They played mostly in Division 1, except in 1965 and 1970.
        Nice finished second in 1973 and 1976 but was relegated in 1981–82.
        After three years in Division 2, Nice returned to the top flight in 1985 but dropped again after six seasons.
        \n\n
        In 1997, Nice won the Coupe de France, defeating Guingamp 5–4 on penalties, though they were relegated soon after.
        After five seasons in Ligue 2, they returned to Ligue 1 for the 2001–02 season.
        Initially, they failed to meet DNCG financial requirements but successfully appealed and were reinstated.
        In 2006, Nice reached the Coupe de la Ligue final but lost 2–1 to Nancy.
        \n\n
        In June 2016, a Chinese-American consortium led by Chien Lee and Alex Zheng acquired 80% of the club, with Paul Conway’s Pacific Media Group holding 2% and Jean-Pierre Rivere retaining 20%.
        Chien Lee became chairman.
        Under Lucien Favre, Nice finished third in the 2016–17 Ligue 1 season and qualified for the UEFA Champions League third round.
        \n\n
        On 11 June 2018, Patrick Vieira replaced Lucien Favre as manager.
        Nice finished 7th in the 2018–19 season.
        In July 2019, British businessman Jim Ratcliffe acquired the club for €100 million.
        After poor results, Vieira was sacked and replaced by Adrian Ursea, who guided Nice to 9th in 2020–21.
        \n\n
        On 28 June 2021, Christophe Galtier was appointed as head coach.
        A year later, on 27 June 2022, Lucien Favre returned but was dismissed mid-season and replaced by reserve coach Didier Digard.
        For the following season, Francesco Farioli took over as head coach.
        In the 2023–24 Ligue 1 season, Nice finished 5th, qualifying for the UEFA Europa League.
    </string>
    <string name="footer_text">© 2025 Defit Saputra. All rights reserved.</string>
</resources>